pippa.io 2018-10-28

# Privacy

[Pippa, Inc. ](https://pippa.io/) (“Pippa”) delivers podcast technology services. This policy explains what information we collect when you use Pippa’s sites, services, mobile applications, products, and content (“Services”). It also has information about how we store, use, transfer, and delete that information.

### **Information We Collect & How We Use It**

In order to give you the best possible experience using Pippa, we collect information from your interactions with our product. Some of this information you actively tell us (such as your email address, which we use to track your account or communicate with you). Other information, we collect based on actions you take while using Pippa, such as what pages you access and your interactions with our product features (like episodes, audio files, and shows). This information includes records of those interactions, your Internet Protocol address, information about your device (such as device or browser type), and referral information.

We use this information to:

  * provide, test, improve, promote and personalize Pippa Services
  * deliver helpful customer service
  * fight spam and other forms of abuse
  * generate aggregate, non-identifying information about how people use Pippa Services

When you create your Pippa account, and authenticate with a third-party service (like Twitter, Facebook or Google) we may collect, store, and periodically update information associated with that third-party account, such as your lists of friends or followers. We will never publish through your third-party account without your permission.

#### **Credit Cards**

All credit card information is handled securely by our credit card processor,  [Stripe](https://stripe.com/). Pippa does not collect, store, or process your credit card information. We make use of your credit card information only to process payments related to the Pippa Services you have expressly approved. To the extent that we do interact with or access your credit card information, we never share it with any third parties.

#### **Public Podcasts**

Users sign up with Pippa mostly for the public dissemination of their podcasts, that is, distributing their audio files and images on publicly available podcast players and websites. However, Pippa does permit users to keep podcasts in ‘draft’ mode (unpublished) or as private feeds (not available for general consumption or secured with a token). In cases where such podcasts are intended for  _public _ consumption (say, where they are already publicly available on iTunes, for example), then Pippa reserves the right to display and refer to these podcasts publicly on Pippa’s website, blog, or elsewhere, including for promotional purposes.

#### **Podcast Statistics**

Pippa collects data about podcast listener activity in order to provide useful analytics for our customers. We log information about each download or stream of an episode including data like IP addresses, user-agents, and geographic location. This is presented as aggregate, anonymous statistics. Such data does not include any personally identifying information.

### **Information Disclosure**

Pippa won’t transfer information about you to third parties for the purpose of providing or facilitating third-party advertising to you. We won’t sell information about you.

We may share your account information with third parties in some circumstances, including: (1) with your consent; (2) to a service provider or partner who meets our data protection standards; (3) with academic or non-profit researchers, with aggregation, anonymization, or pseudonymization; (4) when we have a good faith belief it is required by law, such as pursuant to a subpoena or other legal process; (5) when we have a good faith belief that doing so will help prevent imminent harm to someone.

If we are going to share your information in response to legal process, we’ll give you notice so you can challenge it (for example by seeking court intervention), unless we’re prohibited by law or believe doing so may endanger others. We will object to requests for information about users of our services that we believe are improper.

#### **Data Storage**

Pippa uses third-party vendors and hosting partners, such as Amazon, for hardware, software, networking, storage, and related technology we need to run Pippa. We maintain various logs of your interactions with Pippa’s services and files which you upload to Pippa, usually for purposes of distributing podcast content. By using Pippa Services, you authorize Pippa to transfer, store, and use your information in the United States and any other country where we operate.

#### **Third-Party Embeds**

Some of the content that you see displayed on Pippa is not hosted by Pippa. These “embeds” are hosted by a third-party and embedded in Pippa. For example: YouTube or Vimeo videos, Imgur or Giphy gifs, SoundCloud audio files, Twitter tweets, GitHub code, or Scribd documents that appear within a Pippa post. These files send data to the hosted site just as if you were visiting that site directly (for example, if you load a Pippa episode page with a YouTube video embedded in it, YouTube receives data about your activity). Pippa does not control what data third parties collect in cases like this, or what they will do with it. So, third-party embeds on Pippa are not covered by this privacy policy. They are covered by the privacy policy of the third-party service.

#### **Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance**

We never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13.

#### **Tracking & Cookies**

We use browser cookies and similar technologies to recognize you when you return to our Services. We use them in various ways, for example to log you in more swiftly, remember your preferences (such as default language), evaluate email effectiveness, and personalize content and other information.

Pippa doesn’t track you across the Internet. We track only your interactions within the Pippa network (which encompasses Pippa.io and custom domains hosted by Pippa).

Some third-party services that we use to provide the Pippa Service, such as  [Google Analytics ](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/), may place their own cookies in your browser. This Privacy Policy covers use of cookies by Pippa only and not the use of cookies by third parties.

#### **Data Security**

We use encryption (HTTPS/TLS) to protect data transmitted to and from our site. However, no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure, so we can’t guarantee security. You use the Service at your own risk, and you’re responsible for taking reasonable measures to secure your account.

### **Modifying or Deleting Your Personal Information**

If you have a Pippa account, you can access, modify or export your personal information, or delete your account.

To protect information from accidental or malicious destruction, we may maintain residual copies for a brief time period. But, if you delete your account, your information and content will be unrecoverable after that time. Pippa may preserve and maintain copies of your information when required to do so by law.

### **Business Transfers**

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, reorganization or sale of assets such that your information would be transferred or become subject to a different privacy policy, we’ll notify you in advance so you can opt out of any such new policy, and you may delete your account before transfer is effective.

### **Communications from Pippa**

By joining Pippa, you agree to permit Pippa to send you communications (such as emails, Slack messages, or Intercom messages) about your account, Pippa’s service changes or new policies or services associated with Pippa. If you delete your Pippa account, Pippa will no longer send you such communications.

When you interact with an communication sent from Pippa (such as opening an email or clicking on a particular link in an email), we may receive information about that interaction.

### **Changes to this Policy**

Pippa may periodically update this Policy. We’ll notify you about significant changes to it either per email or in the Pippa app. The most current version of the policy will always be available here.

### **Questions**

If you have any questions or concerns about this policy, or if you are a Pippa user who wishes to make changes to your account, please contact us at  [info@pippa.io ](mailto:info@pippa.io)
